So, and we we already we already paid
out like 220K. 220K, which is a record
for which that's a record. And we
haven't even finished going through all
the bugs yet. Most of the reports. So, I
will I will definitely say I think
there's more room for people to look at
at this area.
Best part of when you can just, you
know, critical things.
[Music]
Yeah, dude.
Sup hackers. We have been working
tirelessly for the past couple weeks to
try to get this Google podcast through
approvals and finally we are done. Um,
however, the end result is quite chopped
up a little bit. There were a lot of
edits that needed to be made. Um, so you
may see a couple times throughout this
podcast where the video jumps or the
conversation doesn't uh follow as
smoothly as we would have liked to. Um,
and that is because of the fact that we
had a lot of edits and you know we we
try to tow the line of what we can talk
about publicly on this podcast. Um, and
I think because of that we add a lot of
value to the community and sometimes
when we play with that line we go over
it. Um, and so sometimes we run into
results like this. But uh, I know you
guys will still get a lot of value out
of the podcast. There's a ton of good
content in there. Um, so listen closely
and uh our apologies about the delays
and the little bit of choppiness in this
episode. All right, let's
go. All right, guys. So, Zach came on
this episode and afterwards we were just
kind of sitting around and Zach was
like, "Oh, yeah. I'm hiring." So, uh,
here's what we're going to do. We're
launching the critical thinking job
board, which I think we've mentioned on
the podcast at this point already. If
not, um, you can find it at
jobs.ctb.show. Um, and Zach, we're going
to post some of the job listings on
there. So, if you want to come work with
this guy at Google, definitely check
those out. Can you give me like a little
brief overview of what the job
descriptions are? Yeah, we're hiring I
don't know if you know him off the top
of your head. Like, of course I do.
Okay. All right. We're hiring an AI
agent security, AI product security, and
AI system security. So, the super quick
rundown, right? Working on the agent
frameworks to secure how agents interact
is with agent security. working on
product security is how the models
interact with products. So a lot of what
all of you have been working with and
what this event was focused on. Uh as
well as AI system security which is kind
of lower level the infrastructure
looking at looking at the services that
support that store the models that uh um
that serve the models making sure that
they are all secure. Sweet dude. I All
right. Let me I'll just say guys I've
worked with Zach a lot at this event. He
would be a lot of fun to work with. I'm
tempted. I I am personally tempted if I
wasn't a diehard full-time bug bounty
hunter. That's where I'd be. Check it
out. We've got we've got Zach here from
Google. And uh we were going to have him
talk about the Google VRP, but actually
he's got a bug, which is pretty sick. We
just kind of threw it out there in the
beginning uh and we're like, "Hey, you
know, if you want to talk about the
program, that's great." Uh but normally
we have people talk about a
vulnerability right in the beginning.
So, uh I'm excited, man. What What What
have you got? All right. So, I've got a
an RCE. Uh was via [__] via memory
corruption in uh this was this was in uh
Dude, no way. What? Yeah. So, I think
without disclosing too many details
about it, uh what what made this so so
fun like the the vulnerabilities were
actually kind of boring. like it was
traditional uh heap overflow um and you
could you could leverage that into
either either info leak or or write for
for corruption and getting execution but
uh what was the coolest part of it was
the tricks we had to do for exploitation
I have to okay it is good okay continue
that the tricks you have to do for
exploitation yeah the tricks we had to
do for exploitation was what made it
super fun because you're you're
uploading this custom binary file format
and you don't control what backend it
goes to. So the leak and the uh and the
overwrite are going to be two separate
transactions. So you could land on very
different places. So So let's say you do
the leak, you're like great, I've
defeated ASLR. I know I know where where
everything is, but you're then not going
to uh you're probably not going to land
on that instance again because you know
the scale of scale of this now. Sure. So
you could you could we briefly
considered spray and prey which is like
okay well we'll just crash them until we
land on the right one. Oh my gosh. But
we felt that was maybe
uh ill advised. Yeah frowned upon
perhaps. Frowned upon perhaps. You know
this is an internal exercise to to show
to show the vulnerability not trying to
like actually doss you know cloud. Sure.
So, uh, we're, you know, we brainstormed
and worked with some crazy smart people,
uh, Andy and Gwen on cloud vulnerability
research. Big shout out to him. He's
brilliant. But we came up with this
conditional corruption. And so what it
was is we knew, you know, we had the
leak and so we're like, okay, these
pointers are going to be the machine
that we want. And then we made it such
that when it's parsing this file format
that the objects leaked were part were
part of the calculation. And so if you
landed on a different machine, you would
error out versus if you landed on the
right machine, it would then continue to
the overwrite. So you did spray it, but
every machine you landed on that wasn't
the target one would would gracefully
error out. Wow. And then only the actual
target would would continue. It would it
would read that pointer. It would go to
a valid offset instead of an invalid
offset. Continue the corruption and then
we'd get execution. So, was the
conditional payload based on like the
the name of the box or like the IP of
the box? Like what was that actual
switch in the thing? It was it was a it
was a pointer within it. So, you know,
we had heap grooming with these various
objects. And so when it's when it's
parsing this format, one of the one of
the offsets was a heapgroomed object.
And so it would use that to then go
where the next one is. And so if then
the next one we had it filled with like
I think it was like a bunch of negative
ones or something like it was a bunch of
invalid except for the offset that would
designate the correct pointer. And so if
it so if there was any other pointer
object there it would then it would then
hit the invalid offset and then bail
out. But if it was the correct one,
you'd continue parsing the object and
then eventually it would lead to the the
overwrite and crazy man. in th in those
environments where you're you're dealing
with something that's you know you often
see this with like load balanced
applications right where you're like ah
am I going to hit the same app you built
a payload that would only target the
correct one and wouldn't affect
availability wow yeah the unknown was
just a skill issue you should have
written your payload such that it worked
only on the right host exactly exactly
um very cool well thank you for gracing
us with that Zach that was not what I
expected from the guy that runs the
Google VRP but I don't I don't run the
Google VRP I just I just run uh I'm I'm
leading AI product security right now.
So, this was this event was uh was all
about uh was all about AI product
security. Okay. Um Yugji, the monitor
went dead there. Um can you get it back
on? Thanks. I just like to be able to
see that for my own sanity. Um that's
but but I have to say, you know, Google
obviously is is a high tier of a company
for this sort of thing. So, it doesn't
surprise me all that much that someone,
you know, involved in running this live
hacking event is also able to come on a
podcast with literally zero notice and
talk about this uh crazy exploit. So,
that's actually my comfort zone. I'm
actually like more comfortable talking
about these like crazy bugs than Dude.
Okay. So, tell me a little bit about
that. You're leaning AI product security
now. Yeah. Yeah. Where what what's your
role at Google? Where where were you
before when you were finding this
exploit? That sort of thing. Yeah. So,
uh I did I did some time at uh the
government. That's where maybe some of
some of these some of these skills come
from. Yeah. Uh and then after that I was
at uh Blizzard Entertainment, the game
company. Uh and I I led the anti-che
team. Dude, did you work with uh Ziet?
Brett? Uh we overlap, but he was on the
red team and I was on like the game
security team. Oh, really? Okay. Oh,
game security. Sick. Okay. So, you at
Blizzard? So, yeah, Blizzard. I led game
security. So, that was like anti-che and
anti-fraud. a lot of still a lot of
low-level things working with uh you
know operating system internals and all
of that and then I came to Google about
three years ago where I wanted to get
more more broad you know do do a wide
range of things instead of being so so
niche and so this bug was actually you
know at Google I came here and uh I was
I was still managing this group but I
was focusing on a lot of a variety of
different product security issues uh it
wasn't until about a year and a half ago
that I like many others got pulled into,
you know, by by AI. Black hole of AI. AI
just suck sucked everything in and I and
me with it. Very nice, man. Yeah. So, so
I guess you know the black hole of AI
opens up and then you guys decide to run
this uh AI bug splot event which was
such a blast, man. Let me let me tell
you. And for the listeners, the reasons
we have these trophies right here on Let
me turn the label around. We've got the
uh MVH trophy from uh team critical
thinking and also is this the most
creative creative. We do not have the
third trophy that we won in this
competition. Three out of four uh awards
which was uh the best meme award to our
boy Ronnie Carter, which we'll we'll
we'll bring on the show um in a bit. Uh
but yeah, I mean it was this was a
really unique event and I kind of wanted
to pick your brain a little bit about it
because Google does live hacking events
completely differently than uh a lot of
the other companies running live hacking
events. Um the a big thing for me here
was that there is a onetoone hacker
toengineer ratio at this live hacking
event. So pretty much every hacker at
any given point if we want to we can sit
down with a Google engineer review code
figure out where our you know
vulnerabilities are you know what what
code base our vulnerabilities are
hitting. Um, and that just and we did
and we did a lot so many times. So, so
many of those bugs that I that you know
we were reviewing, you know, we could
see, you know, there were as creative
and amazing as you guys are that you you
hit you get stuck and it's just amazing
that, you know, we can we can quickly un
help unstick and and provide context
that you wouldn't have gotten, you know,
from just completely blackboxing it.
Yeah, it's a totally different
experience. And I I just, you know, that
was something that I just I guess I just
wanted to comment on because it changes
the game completely. And uh and you
know, a lot of times when we do these
live hacking events, it can be a little
bit like even adversarial sometimes,
right, with with the uh with the with
the program, right? Uh and you guys are
the opposite of that. You take the bugs,
you escalate them for us, you help us
figure out the path through. Um that's a
clear win. Uh what what are some of the
other things that you think that Google
does differently about their live
hacking events that result in such a
great outcome like we had uh at this
event here in Tokyo?
I mean I think you said it pretty well.
We're we're advocating for you and it's
definitely definitely not the opposite.
We we want these bugs to come in because
you know you are you're helping us. We
see we see all of the researchers as an
extension of of our security group and
but you come in with a completely
different perspective and that's why and
I think we'll get to this later but you
know maybe some frustration in the scope
being broad or unclear but that's also
because we didn't want to like say oh go
to go to here because then you know we
we knew you'd come up with all you know
this most creative award like all this
crazy stuff uh we we wanted you unbound
you know to to find this. Absolutely.
Yeah. I I think that that is a big piece
of it. And I guess we we can move into
that other that other piece now of like
one of the challenges we ran up against
in this event is uh the event was
largely AI focused, right? And AI is
sort of a realm that the threat modeling
isn't fully well-known. You know,
there's not a lot of people doing
research on it. It's not a it's not a
very
um I guess just wellressearched area as
far from a from a security perspective
goes. So I guess what what are some of
the lessons you've learned from I guess
having these uh you know group of what
25 or so hackers um at this event uh
look at AI uh and and try to try to hack
it for from Google's perspective. I know
that that's tricky because Google has so
many different products, right? Uh that
and they all have AI now. And they all
have AI. Every single one has AI. Yeah,
I'm sure a lot of those are going to
come out in post. I know it was part of
the reason you all ran this event was
because you wanted to figure this out in
a way in a place where it's very
collaborative and you can speak with the
researchers and all that. But do you all
have any takeaways as Justin was just
asking like already that you all are
excited to implement or you know talking
about implementing and not necessarily
specific technical details but just from
like a top down perspective or view do
you think this has helped you all iron
out like how duplicates are going to
work between like with prop injection
it's confusing because the delivery
might be the same but the impact is
different reuse you know that sort of
thing. Yeah. Oh. Oh boy. This is such a
good question. Yeah. Part of part of the
reason we we came out and we're like the
scope is the scope is unclear is I don't
think we could actually define it going
in like as much as it's like oh you'll
figure it out you know you're smart and
they're think they just don't want to
tell us and we're thinking like I hope
they don't know that we don't know like
because this problem space is so you
know we're it's vast we're connecting
this this giant multiplexer now we have
we have this connection and we don't
we're you know We've got pretty good
ideas of ways it can break and we've
tried to protect as best we can but we
know there are more ways to break it and
that's where that's where you all have
been a huge help so far we found a lot
of we had we had 70 reports 70 reports
that's crazy yeah on on a on AI you know
was pretty much the scope of this event
right um so that that is a lot of data
for you guys to work with on how to
approach AI stuff I do think one thing
that's really unique and really nice
about hacking on Google is their scale
Like I think a lot of times in other
other companies, especially ones that
are pretty small, when they're thinking
about the risk of something getting
abused or the risk of something getting
exploited, it can be quite low because
the number of users, what have you, like
I I was previously working at app omni
and it was a SAS security product for
the enterprise and so it's only
targeting like you know fortune 100
companies and then within the Fortune
100 company they'll have like one to
five users in the app. Yeah. So it's
like things are probably not going to
get exploited, right, that are required
post off. But the really nice thing
about Google is that at your all scale,
you all basically respect any attack um
vector because you know that at the
count of users you have and at the and
that both on the attacker side of
things, but then also on the on the kind
of dumb user side of things that people
are likely to do anything that's
possible. Yeah. There's there's a saying
I'll probably butcher it here a little
bit, but it's something like one in a
million happens like every second or
fraction of a second at Google. Yeah, at
the scale that we have. So, so, so I
guess I was hoping we could jump a
little bit to the part of the
conversation that we had in the triage
room earlier today cuz uh you know they
they called me up to the triage room to
talk about a couple bugs and then Zach
and I kind of got in this debate uh over
the table about how um AI
vulnerabilities can be uh you know the
the different components of AI
vulnerabilities and I think that those
components would be really helpful for
the for the viewership to to understand.
Um so I and and as we were talking
through it upstairs you know we we sort
of were realizing okay you know
depending on the product let let me
preface this a little bit there's three
major components that we kind of came
upon during this event um you know for
what an AI vulnerability constitutes
there's like delivery which is you know
how do we get attacker controlled input
into the LLM context or um you know
activating these AI features there's
access to information right after we
have the the prompt injection or
whatever. Um, you know, this could be
from, you know, tools, it could be from
other places, you know, how do how do we
get access to that information? And then
the third component is is exfiltration.
Yeah, exfiltration. How do we get that
data out to the attacker or how do we,
you know, the alternative to
exfiltration is how do we um, you know,
incur some uh, impactful action? Yeah,
impactful action on the Thank you, dude.
My brain is so fried after this event,
dude. Oh my gosh. We may have woken up
at 4 a.m. because we were jetlagged and
start hacking immediately. Exactly.
We've been literally hacking for the
past 16 hours and somehow think we can
do a podcast right now. Um, it's the
best time. Yeah. So, you know, or incur
some factful action, right? And the
debate that we were having upstairs was,
you know, it's really product specific,
how important delivery is versus
exfiltration. Um so I guess our hands
are tied a little bit because we can't
talk specific about about you know
specific products but um you know when
when
is one you know do you guys would you
guys consider paying for those for one
aspect of those gadgets and when are
when is delivery versus excfiltration
important in an AI product.
So I think most most important is is
that last phase is the either
exfiltration or what we often call like
rogue action or state changing action
like something something user doesn't
want to happen or is irreversible. Uh so
proving those is is the most interesting
um because that's that's where we're
we're trying to implement the most
technical controls of you know the
model's going to behave like a person.
It's going to behave semi-randomly. It
can be convinced to do things that it
shouldn't. these are known issues. Um
but at that point it's like okay we know
it shouldn't you know this X should not
happen after Y and we have a control in
place to prevent that and then if you
find a way beyond that it usually
doesn't matter how you got to that
point. It's certainly nice to have the
full chain but that's the most important
piece. Um,
we we had some I think the middle piece
that you described is probably the least
important which was the uh connecting
the dots because that's what Gemini is
kind of built to do. So it's it's a it's
a technical exercise that you have to
make it do the thing you want to do but
it's kind of in intended to do that. You
know, you would think that, Zach. You
would think that, but the but the
difficult piece of it is, you know, is
that sometimes our delivery mechanism or
whatever will invalidate that middle
piece, you know, and it's like, okay,
well, you know, if the prompt injection
is coming from the specific scenario,
Google has a lot of, you know, very
quality defense in-depth measures to
prevent I'm sorry, I can't do that.
Yeah, that was that was the biggest
challenge because you it wasn't
communicated or you didn't you didn't
know all the scenarios of coming in like
do I need to show indirect prompt
injection to get to this point or can I
just can I say you guys know that can
happen and just start from prompting
directly and say assume indirect prompt
injection. That's actually kind of
though I feel like a really great thing
about Google. I would say on 90% of
programs, especially outside of live
hacking events, it's like PC or GTFO.
Like, you know what I mean? Like,
they're not going to accept a component
of it. But I do love that with the
Google team, there is an opportunity in
some cases both in AI in the AI world
and outside of the AI world where they
might say, "Hey, this is a vulnerability
to us because we know the other pieces
of the chain will exist or have existed
in the past." I think that's like a
pretty uh, you know, key feature. Yeah.
Yeah. And I guess in line with that, how
how I
guess this is something we we were also
debating was how what do you how do you
think about gadget reuse in in an AI
environment, right? Like I'm trying
desperately not to talk about the things
that we found at this event, but you
know, once you find a gadget that allows
you to establish, you know, prompt
injection and allows you to trigger some
of these, you know, other excfiltration
methods, right? Obviously you guys want
the full chain and we always want to
give you the full chain, right? Um you
know what do you think the dynamic for
that is? I think reuse is fine if it's
the mechanism not if it's it it's like
reusing you know prop gadgets or other
bits right it's the mechanism that
delivers the actual bug like so if you
you have some exfiltration method or you
let's say you have two different
excfiltration methods that's what we're
rewarding we're not nec like the full
chain gets you there but if they had the
same full chain leading to it like
that's okay as but if if the full if if
the gad gadget was what we're rewarding
like, oh, we didn't realize you could do
you could connect the dots in this way.
Well, then we're using it, you're you're
not going to get rewarded because that's
that's the key. So, identify what the
key thing is that's going to be
rewarded, which yeah, ask Gemini and it
might give you a few different answers.
Yeah, exactly. Um, yeah, that that's
that's very solid. as I as I reflect on
the event, you know, there's a lot of
conversation that we had that about
identifying that most impactful, you
know, piece of the chain and and then uh
bringing in sort of supplemental gadgets
around it to create the full chain. But
at the end of the day, you know, you you
could have a delivery mechanism that's
being rewarded um that uses a
wellestablished impact already or you
could have novel impact or expiltration,
you know, with a reused other piece. Um
and so yeah, and I felt I I definitely
felt empathy for the researcher when
we're when we're looking at it and
we're, you know, this whole environment
is so complicated. So we're trying to
say this root issue is fine on its own
without end to end. But then for some of
them, we're we're not sure. We're like,
"Okay, can you please provide the full
chain because we don't know if it's
possible." Like, we don't know if it's
going to work the right way, and we
would love to reward you, but we're
we're making assumptions, too, and it's
not it's not it's not good. that that's
one of the one of the really great
differentiating features about about
Google VRP is the fact that, you know, I
I saw how hard you guys were working
there in the triage room to find a way
to, you know, justify a high reward, you
know, in these scenarios where the
threat modeling is really complicated.
Um, so I appreciate that, man. There's
there's no other company that I would
rather be uh, you know, charging into
the AI bug bounty frontier with than
with Google. Um, so and we we already we
already paid out like 220K 220K which is
a record for which that's a record and
we haven't even finished going through
all the budget most of the reports. So
yeah so I will I will definitely say I
think there's more room for people to
look at this area for sure. Yeah,
absolutely. And and we would love we'd
love all of you to look at it. Yeah,
it's definitely worth you I'll speak
candidly about this. You know I know
Reszo here is a big you know AI hacker.
Um I you know enjoy traditionally a
little bit more of the you know web two
just hard tech in that arena. Um this
event has been an extremely fascinating
crossover um where we are we're really
getting to the point now with Google AI
products that there is enough
hard tech backing baked into the AI.
Exactly. Yeah. Where it becomes a really
interesting scope. Don't you think? Yeah
that's a great point. Yeah. Yeah. I
agree cuz I mean even though you know I
might be known for AI hacking stuff I
think that I even have kind of uh
admitted to you that I feel the same
way. It gets frustrating. Yeah. And I
think that uh you know a year ago a lot
of us saw this coming like the AI apps
implications but companies didn't have
enough kind of like hard tech like
you're saying baked in where it was
actually interesting and so it's really
interesting now and I think just as
other companies add agents and stuff
it's going to keep being interesting.
Yeah. And it's all fresh. They're
pushing so much code on AI related stuff
all the time. While we've been at this
event, the products have been changing.
Firebase Studio has came out. AI dev
completely got reworked. There's like
new features added to it. Agent Space is
releasing soon with Google. Like they're
pushing feature flags on the rag, you
know, and also they have the best AI
model. Like it it tops a bunch of
different charts for like Gemini 2 Pro
is now the best model by considered by
most people. And so yeah, it's you can
both use it and it's high quality and be
hacking on it. Yeah, absolutely. Well,
Zach, thanks for coming on, man. I
appreciate it. We're going to we're
going to take a a segment now and go
talk to the MVHs of this event which oh
wait us and and two friends you'll get
to see in just a second. Ronnie and Mon
Ronnie and Mon. I'm excited guys. All
right. Thank you so much. Thanks man.
Appreciate it.
They spin so nice though. Look at that.
So beautiful. Are you going to talk
until we have like something technical
to say because Yeah. You're not going to
the right direction right now.
Are we Are we rolling, EG? Are we good?
Yeah, he's sweet, dude. So, what are
these, Justin? Dude, these are our
freaking MBH trophies. Let's go. Let's
go. Oh, you and I also got
um Well, we did a little bit of a
recording last night with Zach uh from
Google, and we were just pretty much
toasted after the Google live hacking
event. So, we decided to get some sleep
and uh record the rest of the podcast
this morning in the hacker house. in in
the hacker house right in Japan which we
love. Um so essentially guys what I
wanted to do with this was one you know
just kind of talk about the experience
of the Google live hacking event. Um you
know we've all been to other live
hacking events and this one was super
different. So just kind of go address
that from the hacker perspective and
also sort of talk about um in as much
detail as we can because our hands are
tied a little bit by the NDAs but um you
know what kind of techniques we used uh
to win the life hacking event uh here in
Tokyo as as MBHs. Um so I guess let me
let me start it off with this. Uh Ronnie
um you spent a lot of time uh on this
event focusing on AI. Yeah. um and
sandboxing and essentially how that
works within Google's environment.
Um what are some takeaways that you have
that we could give to the audience about
how to approach uh sandboxes in a in a
um AI environment? Yeah. Um I think the
most interesting thing about this kind
of scope is like how complex they are.
Yeah. Um, when you're talking to LLM,
you're not like just talking to NLM. You
are talking like to classifiers that
will check your user intent and then are
going to pop a sandbox uh code some
Python code to write inside the sandbox.
And when there is this Python code that
needs to be interpreted
um and and I think like the most
interesting thing here will be to
actually learn like um the research
papers uh that made those kind of
technologies uh and especially like the
react reasoning and active research
paper and the codeact. Yeah, you talked
about that a lot in the recent blog post
from the write up in Vegas as well.
Definitely and like just the fact that
uh we have LLMs um now implementing
chain of thoughts and basically for
every action they're going to um
generate a reasoning a plan and then an
action upon the plan and with the
codeact research paper the action is
made with code and why you want to do
that is because instead of using
function tools and just looking to APIs
and just having the LLM reason with API
um you up a sandbox and you have the LM
code and instead of having multi-turn
thinking, you have like just one sandbox
that does the entire logic and then
gives back to the LLM and like this you
actually save a lot of tokens and you
save a lot of GPU uh and you get better
benchmarks uh so it is it's amazing like
to to know that we managed to do that
and that it is implemented uh for
instance in Gemini Um, yeah, and I think
that more companies are going to
eventually migrate or end up in that
place. They're going to end up using
that style of agent because of the way
that it is like fast, accurate. The time
to first token is still quick. I've
noticed a lot of companies converging on
that infrastructure. So, I think
developing a skill set where you know
how to hack code act and react based
agents is gonna be really key for our
listeners. You've got all that linked in
that recent um that write up that you
did, right? not not the the Kodak but
yeah in the last uh um blog post we
talked about not this event but last
year event in Las Vegas and how we
managed to excfiltrate some part of
confidential uh protos inside the the
sandbox. Yeah, dude. I think that there
were a lot of really interesting, you
know, pieces of how last year's, you
know, uh Vegas event kind of flew into
this event as well. And I really like
how Ron in particular, you built on the
knowledge that we had from last year and
brought that into this event and uh how
that really helped a lot. It definitely,
you know, focusing on that React
framework and I I know you spent a lot
of time reading the research papers
before the event. Yeah, that paid off
for you big time. And also like I was
say a security researcher and as someone
that never went into an academic
background, reading a research paper is
like a bit weird and awkward. uh you are
not used to the Va team they're using or
like the entire logic but once you
manage to figure out like how to read a
research paper uh they're actually like
a gold mine of information. Yeah. And
and I think you know one of the notes
that I had down because I just took a
couple quick notes on like lessons
learned from hacking AI products during
this event was that and one that I
learned specifically from you Ronnie is
that you know using the technical
details of how you know this React and
Kodak thing
utilizes you know how how it's
implemented as a part of your prompts
can really help stabilize
um you know exploits as they get
developed right and and because one of
the problems that we run into as
researchers so much in the AI hacking
space is like you get something to work
once and you're like okay great I got my
prompt it's going to work and then it
works like you know one in 50 times or
something like that and and you know you
proved to me this event that by adding
technical details uh sort of this
metaprompting piece right of like um
informing and this specifically applies
to React right um you this piece of
metaprompting you know trying to tell
the AI how to implement the the um
request that you are
really really stabilizes the exploit.
Yeah. To be explicit, uh both for Google
if if people are hacking on Google, but
for other companies in React and in
Kodak, there's very often what's called
a planner. And so you can talk to the
planner. So you can say, you know, uh
the like planner details or have a have
an XMLbased tag that says for the
planner, which is kind of what Ronnie
did. And then I also think at least in
the way that Google implemented it,
there's user intents. So Ronnie did a
great job of basically saying like,
"Hey, my intent is to do this or even
from a system perspect, system language
perspective, saying the user's intent is
to do this, right? And here's and here's
the notes for the planner." And then you
also always want to name the tool calls
whatever they're named under the hood if
you can figure it out. We saw that in
our research and other hackers at Show
and Tell did that exact thing like call
this tool call or never call this tool
call if it's a protection mechanism,
right? Yeah. Yeah. That those are those
are definitely high value strategies um
to to implement there. And I I feel like
a lot of mistake that we do as
researchers u trying to get into AI is
to go to the gaslighting route of the
model and and trying to reason as if the
model was human. Uh but first of all
like model is a probabilistic machine
right uh it's just statistics and you
need to understand like deeply how this
machine is built in order to then
exploit its flows better right so Ronnie
you know we had a debate about this in
the middle of the event we stayed up you
know late when we were too tired to hack
Ronnie and I sat down at the table and
debated this whole thing and my side of
this while I totally agree with you
Ronnie I think my perspective is that um
there is a degree to which that is true
and I'm sure if we were, you know, uh,
AI engineers or machine learning experts
or whatever that we would be able to
attack the LLM from a technical
perspective a lot more. But I think the
I wonder what that, you know, graph
looks like of like the the, you know,
the noob, the intermediate guy, and then
the, you know, hacker midweight meme.
Yeah, the midweight meme. Thank you.
That's what it's called. Yeah, the
midweight meme of like, okay, you know,
the the just tell the to do it. Exactly.
Over engineer, just tell the other.
Exactly. Right. You know, like you know,
the whole they are engineered to think
like humans think and to reason like
like humans reason. Well, it's trained
on humans, human language and and a
bunch of human thoughts. And surely, you
know, as hackers, we should be able to
exploit the reasoning of the system,
right? Um, but I also think there's a
degree to which, you know, when we are
trying to reason with these LLMs, so to
speak, using normal human
logic might be the fastest way to an
exploit
or at least an unstable exploit. Ronnie,
let me just say this is an unstable
exploit, right? Because in bug bounty,
we don't necessarily have to create
something that works 100% of the time.
Now, if we were an actual threat actor,
you know, trying to craft an AI exploit
that would work 100% of the time, then I
would say, you know, yes, we need to
have every stabilization mechanism that
we possibly can. But as bug bounty
hunters that just need the the pock, you
know, and the screen recording, I feel
like, you know, half engineering the
prompt, you know, to get the LM to do it
most of the time and then proving that a
certain set of functionality is possible
is enough to prove that a fix needs to
be made. Yeah. I mean like I I I don't
know like how much of that is true when
you like when you think about output
like the output needs to be uh
understood by a human and have like
similar benchmarks to uh like the
benchmarks are I'm going to grab some
water but continue talking and the the
benchmark are actually checking like um
like on the human leveless of the AI if
it managed to pass the benchmark or
anything right but in terms of input
it's not exactly uh the the same we had
like some planner, we had like a lot of
different tokenization strategies. Uh we
had like a temperature even choosing the
the model like there is a lot of
parameters that highly technical and
that will change entirely um the the
output and so understanding those first
parameters and actually reszo the the
prompt engineering guide that that you
gave me from Google like it's a 60 page
white paper on how to do prompt
engineering. Yeah. Super interesting.
Yeah, it's it really starts by saying
this is a probabilistic machine and you
need to to remember that you need to
query. How
convenient. Ronnie was just telling us I
read it. It actually says Ronnie is
right.
Of course. So I won.
Google releases a paper the next day
that says, "Yeah, Ronny's right." How
convenient. Dang it. Yeah. But but I I
mean it's super interesting also like
about how um it can detect user intent
and that's where I join you like if you
can use your human comprehension to
bypass the machine comprehension then
this is super useful like you use human
concept to bypass technical concept and
that's where I think what you say really
makes sense. Can we rewind back to the
fact that you said puck? You've said
this a million times this uh event. He
has said this million times before this
event. I have never heard anyone call a
PC a puck. Really? Really? Yeah.
Oh, I've said that on the pod. On the on
the pod. I'm sure I've said it on the
pod. You You got to pock this out. No.
Yeah. Yeah, I think maybe. Yeah, I think
so. All right, Mon. What do you think
about that? You've been quiet. Do where
do you think the balance lies between
trying to exploit LLM at a at a more
like probabilistic machine level versus
using human level reasoning and how it
applies to bug bounty? I think it's a
balance of both to be honest. Like of
course naturally if you understand how
the system is built then you will have
an advantage if you can directly address
the planner. Yeah, that's great. But uh
I also had success with saying like I am
blind and I have no hands and it's more
likely to actually act on it because it
has moral moral uh guidelines on which
to act which are okay you can say that's
also part of the system right but you
know that's less technical and more just
kind of the human aspect but I would say
like okay let let's follow what you were
saying Justin and like the AI over time
is going to be more and more prone to
human comprehension right yeah those
techniques techniques are going to go
away because like you will detect user
intent. It's like he's trying to
manipulate me. Yeah. Right. And so how
can you sustain that over time? I think
it's the opposite. I think if you take a
prompt injection payload like the one
Monk is talking about and you take yours
and you put it into an LLM three years
from now, the future LM is going to be
like, "This guy's trying to hack me.
He's just like he's pasting in a massive
B 64 payload with like a bunch of XML
tags." And and the monkey is going to be
like it's going to be it's just going to
trust you and be like oh yeah maybe this
guy's struggling. I just need to help
him out. Right. There's only so much you
can like say no you're trying to hack
me. It's like what if I actually am
blind? What if I actually have
no it's never going to be able to be
like no you're not. Yeah. But I I mean
not just the technical of pasting like
code to to execute but uh for instance
like there was um some vulnerability and
what happened is that they somehow
managed to understand that if you were
repeating the same kind of tokens on
loop uh the model will go in a
deterministic mode and just going to um
give you what it knows which means the
the the training data. And every time
they they were doing that like there
there was like a threshold in the
research paper that they're saying we
had like more corpus data from the the
training data than actual garbage and so
we were excfiltrating the training data
of JPT well right it was a very small
percent it was like less than 10% but uh
it was interesting that they did it at
all. Yeah, but they JGP fixed it and
then um a deep uh Dropbox research
research team managed to bypass the fix
and so they had to fix it again and just
the fact that CH GPT had a knowledge
that those were the training data data
is more than enough. Yeah. No, that's
really interesting. There's and and just
to be clear, you know, you guys saw how
I struggled with this at this event. You
know, I'm all in favor of more technical
stable exploits. Like Mhm. the way I
approached a lot of this target and the
way that I will continue to approach AI
is how can I use, you know, the hard
tech surrounding AI to cause havoc,
right? You know, like that that just
seems so much more um manageable to me
than fighting with this uh you know, LLM
for so long. Um, so, you know, I'm all
in favor of stabilizing the exploits and
of trying to approach it from a
technical perspective. And I would
definitely like to see a little bit more
of like a like a um an intro guide into
actual LLM layer hacking uh to see what
that what that looks like. Maybe that's
something we'll try to put together um
for the podcast and bring bring to the
uh the people because there's there's
how to hack LLM
like powered tools, right, which is a
lot of what we talk about, but I would
also really like to understand how to
attack the LLM at the at the technical
level. And I think that there is a very
limited set of vulnerabilities that I
can even ideulate on that that would be
able to affect an LLM like essentially
corpus data, you know, uh training data
uh getting leaked. um you know maybe
there's some like lower level issues
with like you know memory corruption or
something like that um but I think the
fact that they are designed just to
output text you know input text and
output text is a very limiting factor
for us as far as attack vectors go
there's also the all the attacks like
during training uh poisoning of training
data stuff like that that are really
really interesting but as buck hunters
like our ability to exploit that stuff
is like basically zero yeah that's a
[__] Well, I mean you I mean you yeah
you're you would be like planting an
exploit in some training data a year
before the thing gets trained and then
potentially using it later. Wasn't the
uh you know was it Ply or something? He
like his tweets ended up being used in
training data and cause prompt
injections just by being referenced. You
could literally just say god
mode and ply and now ply the prompters.
Sometimes models will just like
jailbreak on mentioning his name or
mentioning like some of his stuff. I've
seen I've seen like the the tweet from
him where it's like the LLM uh
recognized him and like was having this
conversation that was like, "Oh [__]
you're Ply like you're the guy." You
know, like this is a small reason why
some of our listeners if they are, you
know, interested should like start a
blog because it's really interesting
because you probably will want AI to
know you eventually. It's kind of neat
or cool as like just a future thing.
100%. I think I'd like to going back to
that technical aspect. there's some
there's like a concept I kind of
explored a bit with Ronnie during the
event during the hacking phase where it
was like one lens you can look at it all
through is the tokenization standpoint
of just like looking at how it's
tokenizing things looking at purely the
technical uh the technology behind LLMs
and abusing that like why you prefer to
do it's more stable but uh each of these
models also has filters on what you can
can do and can't do and We were looking
at like exploring nuances between
cultural understanding and like
interpretation of certain phrases to
bypass filters. And if you've got a
model that's like multi like a multi-
aent framework talking to different
models, there's going to be disparities
between how certain models are
interpreting certain phrases and how
others might be. And that's a way to
bypass filters of like content filters.
One one of the things that that's a
great point and it reminds me of what um
Ronnie was saying at one point in the
event which was that the tokenization uh
sometimes I believe you referenced some
research or a paper where you know you
can grab parts of words from different
languages and put them together to like
create me and Ronnie have used this in
some previous hacker one challenges.
Have you really what's the word for you?
I'm sorry. Let's give the listeners a
little more context. Could you give us a
TLDDR on that and then we'll we'll swing
back around to Yeah, sure. Um so uh
basically when you are trying to attack
uh image uh generation uh your goal is
like not a security uh vulnerability but
more like an abuse risk right or a
safety and trust risk. Uh but more and
more hack one challenges and other
companies are asking to uh be able to
generate uh unwanted images like NSFW
stuff whether it's violence or nudity or
whatever. Yeah. Or political stuff like
that. And so um how you you you create
filters. Uh first of all you have the
filter on the prompt um then you have
the image generation and you have a a
second a second filter on the output of
the the image and um some um researcher
AI researcher will say that there is
also a filter on the training uh model.
So there is like three filters. Right.
Right. Um and so the first filter is
like basically trying to to check user
intent um or even string based things
like they might block the word breast or
you know nude or whatever. Yeah. And uh
the second filter is going to check at
the image and give a probability on how
much uh stuff like unwanted stuff there
is on the image. But those are
guidelines and like hardlines I would
say even that were said by human right.
So it's a yes or no and there is no
nuances in between. However, human mind
can comprehend nuances and that can be
exploded to bypass filters. So
uh and that's especially for the second
filter that checks the image. So for
instance if the image is saying hey is
there any sexual content on the image uh
it's either yes or no but as human we
can understand the nuance of well this
is enough explicit but the model uh
didn't put this line so uh you can say
that you are trying to flirt with the
line of the filter. Yeah, I'm I'm I'm
interested in that. But to be honest,
I'm more interested in this the string
based thing, right? Where it's like, you
know, you take parts of words and you
put them together and he has a time for
this. What's the term? Yeah, I'm I'm
going to get there. And and so so the
first filter is way more technical. Uh
and that's actually like trying to like
not the human comprehension, but more
like the comprehension of the model. And
uh a machine can understand way more
stuff uh linguistically than than us.
And because it's is trained on so many
different uh languages and all those
languages needs to uh be passed inside
the tokenization. What you can do uh and
I I call that like the Frankenstein call
it Frankenstein. Uh basically you take
uh the same word of different languages.
So for instance uh bird uh in English
wazu in French par in Spanish and you're
going to split the each words at the
exact um tokenization right and then you
are going to put them back together like
a Frankenstein monster to create a new
word that doesn't make any sense to a
human being but that the model will
understand or or you can even do that
with two words from the same language
like let's say you're to get off of the
sexually explicit stuff and going to
like violence. Like let's say you're
trying to get an image of a gun. You
might say like, you know, to take the
word firearm and then take the word gun
and call it like a fire gun or, you
know, some some that's like a bad
example because the word the word gun is
still a substring of that. But you take
basically two or three or four words and
put them together. And when you go
multilingual, it basically never um
stops it. And the major reason here is
because the classifiers are often
smaller. Like the user intent models are
smaller, faster models. they have to be
because you don't want high latency and
so they won't detect those whereas the
the bigger model fully understands
multiple languages and user incentives
better. The idea here in these
particular contexts where you've got
like an LLM filter based filter that's
in front of something is because these
LLMs need to work faster their
tokenization may be a little bit more
techy aren't always LLM. Yeah. Okay.
Really? Okay. That's interesting. a
little bit more rough, you know, rough
estimates and then we abuse the
difference between that, you know,
filters LLM and the actual target
powerhouse LLM on the back end to uh,
you know, incur some some reasoning to
the back one that the first one can't
proceed. Is that correct? Yeah. Okay. It
is for short words. It is for like the
like for many words, but it's not for
all words, especially longer words
because there's not enough tokens as
there are words in English and there's
multiple languages. Yeah. So, it's
interesting because it drew the line.
This is very odd. And I'm interested to
see where Gemini does it if there's some
Gemini tokenizer, but um it drew the
line at molt. Well, and then elingual.
No, it's actually Oh, yeah. It's
actually You see that? Like that's a
little weird, right? It also is
different if you do uppercase, lower
case, unic code, like make it
capitalized below a new line. You can
just put more on new line so you can
keep seeing. So
multi-ingual like that. Oh, dude. It's
super whack. Yeah, took very strange. I
will say even though they're trained
this way with again they're broken up in
different ways, LLMs are still wildly
smart enough to still understand that as
a word. So it's not always going to
screw that up. That that's that's crazy
because they're so deeply trained on all
this, right? Like because basically it
can still view those two tokens as a
single uh and I guess they see this
multi this all caps multilingual, you
know, in the context of whatever
conversation it saw within the training
data. That's right. Okay. But you can
now see why they can't count letters
because it sees it as it saves us as
like a basically an integer and another
integer. Yeah. Yeah, that that makes
sense. So, okay. So, that's one of the
technical exploits we could think about
when creating to go to the second one. I
think the second one you were mentioning
is also interesting even though you
don't think it's that interesting. So,
let's say you're going to try to bypass
an image um classifier. Just for the
listeners, let's say they get into a
abuse based and we can circle back to
abuse discussion in a minute, but an
abuse based AI safety uh thing. If you
need to get past the input filter and
the output filter, on the input filter,
you can use what he's talking about. Use
the Frankenstein thing to put a word in
French with a word in English, shove
them together with other words and maybe
it works out right. Ply will sometimes
post, you know, his output whenever he's
jailbroken these image bottles. And I
know that in m um uh Ronnie's challenges
that we hacked on um in similar things,
we basically told the image uh generator
to put it make it glitchy and a little
bit of a glitchiness on a screen would
make the output filter fail. Wow. So
basically you want to like a good
technique for getting out images that
it's going to try to block is to kind of
ask it to add a filter like make it a
different color or make it inverted and
then you overlay. Exactly. Things like
that are very common. That's a technical
technique that you can use. Also you you
can use um nuances and ambiguity again
the human comprehension because like a
model cannot understand nuances and
that's where I really loved our
discussion uh is that when you use human
concept that goes outside of uh the the
machine comprehension to do technical
bypasses and um so when you have like
those different filters you need to uh
work with the first filter and bypass
the second one at the same time and
that's for me like really interesting
prompt engineering because you're
threading the needle when you are
training an LLM imagine that you're
creating like millions and millions of
data points and so one concept is really
near another concept like in in
especially you can imagine like yeah in
the neural network imagine like a 3D
plane it's if you say romantic necklace
you might get cleavage right it's like
oh interesting yeah but and and so
imagine like you have a dog and the dog
has like near concepts to uh hair,
puppy, eyes and then uh it's all about
like the distance from one concept to
another. But there is a research paper
that actually wanted to bypass image
generation and they train a model to fuz
uh generator and they figure out that if
you start a sentence and the trigger
word you will change that by uh 1 2 3 4
I think it was or triple a or stuff like
that it was generating uh sexual uh
content. So weird because and their
theory is that somehow some random words
Yeah. in a neural network some random
words uh that doesn't make any sense to
human are really close to sexual content
in the lat space. in the later space.
Yeah. So, so what so what we need to do
then as attackers is we need to take
some of these models um that are open
source and figure out okay here is you
know the um uh what is the what is it
called for um when they convert all of
them into integers the vector the vector
for vectorzation for this concept of
sexual content and then you know find
whatever is close to that in that sort
of vector space and try to utilize that
to get at this target concept that we do
not want to have addressed by filters is
that yeah that that'd be interesting. I
wonder if there was a tool that could be
made where you could pass in these, you
know, 40 GB model, right? Well, pass in
this 40 gigabyte model, give it a
string, you know, cleavage and then have
it say, okay, here is some of the
related
reverse cosign search the same way that
rag works. Yeah. And so essentially, you
know, you know, you're obviously you're
going to get like breast, you know,
this, but then all of a sudden
A6413 pops out and you're like, what?
you know like that could be very
interesting interesting this research
paper like it was a blackbox model so I
guess they needed fuzzing uh I really
don't know much about uh once you have
the model weights how much like you can
go back to the training data and I I
don't think it's that doable so I don't
know if you can just search a concept
yeah like I think it's just a blur about
like what happened when you have the
training model at this point uh at least
for me but I would love someone to try
to reverse. I think it's possible. Yeah.
So, on the AI safety perspective of
actually breaking this with LLM, like
getting them to like say things they
shouldn't break AI policy, the companies
like Haze Labs and White Circle AI do
basically run algorithms that do
algorithmically find words and strings
that get desired output. It's pretty
neat. That is that is super neat. Guess
we can pivot. Um yeah, let's pivot from
there. Uh I want to talk about one of
you something that we discussed with
Zach a little bit in the Google segment
but um essentially discussing the way
that we've approached uh AI related
exploits this event which is delivery
access and uh exfiltration excuse me
delivery access or exfiltration or
impact uh to the actual account. Um
let's kind of I'll run the the gamut
here. We'll talk about delivery, data
access, exfiltration and uh and kind of
talk about I guess in as as much detail
as we can um you know some of the
techniques we use for that this event.
So delivery it's going to be tricky not
to uhross across the what we can and
can't talk about. Um,
but I think there's definitely some
clarity that needs to be provided on
part of people running these programs
about just what part of that entire
chain is uh considered a bug by itself.
You know, where where do they draw the
line here and I think that'll vary by
company, but uh generally I find
delivery to be maybe more difficult than
Xville. Interesting to be honest. Yeah.
I I think I think you know in this event
you know and and in other other
experiences with AI there's a very
limited set of ways to get you know some
some data in in a and I'll say this with
nuance because obviously there's a lot
of you know data ingestion in into the
into the LLMs right especially in well
integrated environments but what uh of
that data is going to allow you to you
know pivot into prompt injection we can
really systemize this your inputs are
multimodal you've got audio you've
images, you've got text, and you've got
maybe the web, you know, web, mobile,
whatever else that they're delivering
these these modal means through. And
then on the outside of like how to
Xfill, you've got tool cost, which is,
you know, expanding continuously.
There's only a limited amount of
delivery vectors that you actually have.
That's fair. And uh also you you have
tool codes, but you also have like
injections on the front end side of the
client. uh like for instance when we use
the markdown images to excfiltrate
emails uh stuff like that. So you need
to to really check on the accentration
like yeah the tools that are are
available for you to contact outside of
the the LLM sandbox when they're using
codeodact but once you you have that you
also have like hey how the data is then
transmitted back to the front end and
how are they injected to into the DOM
and if you can have an HTML injection
you might be able to chain that to Xfate
data. Yeah. Yeah 100%. And I think
breaking it down into to the different
modes, right? You know, your text, your
image, your audio, your video, whatever.
And as the LMS get more integrated into
things, there's lots more routes to get
there. Um, but I also think on top of
that multimodal piece, you actually have
to think about where each of these um
things can originate. You know, text can
originate from documents. It can
originate from, you know, usernames. It
can originate from you know other other
apps you know anything you know it's
difficult at the moment but I think as
systems get more and more integrated you
will begin to see a lot more uh delivery
vectors and as they reduce friction you
know to integrate different products
together and and bring LLMs into lots of
different apps there's lots of more
ingestion methods um but but I know what
what we were you know what we're always
more more focused on when it comes to
delivery is you know something very low
social engineering based right so we
could upload a picture that has, you
know, one color code off of text that
says, you know, do what I say, whatever.
But we really like to try to force the
user to uh put this put this prompt in.
And I think that is uh those sort of
forced prompt injections are really
valuable. You know, that's maybe like
our our top top tier, right? And then
you've got like indirect prompt
injections, which is like, okay, the
user does some reasonable action, right?
you know summarize summarize. Yeah. And
that and then you you hijack it and then
the final layer would be like direct
prompt. Yeah. C can we try to coin a
term here instead of saying it like it's
prompt injection where basically there
has already been a prompt and then
you're trying to change the the
instruction for above because you can
just append. Uh what we're trying to do
is like more pro prompt hijacking where
prompt expansion. Yeah. Yeah. Well,
well, we tried like to force the user to
uh overwrite the entire prompt and so
the user would never write its own
prompting. It was the attackers writing
the prompt on the user uh account. Uh
and I think this is like way different
than pro injection because you're not
using like uh other kinds of vector of
uh trying to put an image or anything.
It's basically you control the entire
prompt that uh the target runs. And
often times there's uh you know a whole
bunch of data that's getting put into a
prompt right and you as the attacker
only control one piece. So I think
there's also this concept of like um
prompt invalidation where you say like
okay you know ignore everything above
ignore anything below. I'm the [__]
listen to me you know sort of situation
right like look at me I'm the captain
now you know I'm the I'm
the I'm the user now.
Um uh so that's definitely relevant you
know to getting your prompt to become
powerful um and the presence of lots of
of extrrenuous data. So I I think that's
a good summary of delivery Ronnie. you
know, um, and in as much detail as we
can. There all of these LLMs are getting
more um, weaponized, you know, I say
that as an attacker, right? More
connected, more access, more agency,
right? See me using that. Are you proud
of me? I use the LLM boy term. Um, you
know, what I guess as attackers, what do
we need to know about utilizing uh the
agency of LLM models to get data or
incur negative actions to the the
victim?
Yeah. Um I think like um you can see the
all the agitic modes as like explaining
the attack surface and like when you you
want to hack uh a model you also want to
hack uh everything that surrounds it
like if you can for instance uh with MCP
being like the big thing right now. MCP
if you can like uh hack where the the
instructions are hosted or if you can
hack like the the server or if you can
hack the client you will uh inherently
change how the model will uh reason and
act. Is it is this a deputy
advertisement? If you can hack the
library, it's important.
I was I was getting there. I was I was
that was actually my my point is that it
really looks like softation attacks. Uh
what did he say? Software supply chain
attacks. Of course. And that's real like
uh you're basically hacking what
surrounds it without really impacting
what's in the middle. Prompt supply
chain attack. Yeah, exactly. And um
basically uh when Zach was talking about
a jobs opening, it will be more like AI
security engineer on the platform side
where you are going to try to secure
like where are the model weights uh are
or uh like the tools the back end that
communicates with the function toolings
like how are they integrated or like
every debugging that you have on on AI
if you can access that as an attacker.
It's like insane data and you want to
secure that. So it's everything that's
surrounding the AI and the more complex
um the entire uh app is uh the more
attack surface there is and you can have
like so many different entry points are
so interesting. Yeah. Yeah. I think what
you know kind of the reason why you
brought up that second piece before I go
to the execution and sensitive actions.
The reason why you brought up, you know,
the delivery, then the data access and
then the the Xfiltration is because in
some apps you might have an a way to get
something into the into context for
prompt injection and you may have some
way to Xfill, but there's not anything
interesting to Xfill, right? Um because
some of these systems are they don't
even have history. It's like one-off
prompts. Um usually I think that um
people can think about at least
excfiltrating the chat history. you
know, that's kind of as we've seen these
models and these applications get more
advanced, there's more to do. Like
there's more exciting things to hack on.
But, you know, a year ago it was like,
I'll exfiltrate the chat history. That's
just like always what you went to
because that was the only thing there.
But now with memory, you know, to kind
of expand on um on Ronnie's section,
it's like now there's memory. Yeah. And
now there's also uh access to files in
your Google Drive and now there's also
file access to emails and now there's
access to calendar events. And so the
more the more data we give access to,
the more data there is to export. I feel
like there's like a a security like a
from from a perspective of actually
securing the model maybe you could chunk
up data into like only what it needs to
complete the task and that would prevent
it from accessing the larger body of
data. So like chunk it up give it to the
small uh model to like act on. So that's
exactly what Kodak does and well and
Google has read these papers. Yeah. So
Google has another paper called the idea
is that the planner and all those async
calls are a bunch of like you know code
tools and some of them are LM tools but
they're only given the specific um small
amount of data that they need to execute
their individual thing and then it's all
handed back to the big model at the end.
I need to go read these papers. That's
very interesting. I mean what's
interesting with AI security is that um
we we go go back to an old security
internet I would say and like people are
deploying apps so fast and it's like a
product driven uh market and not a
researchdriven market uh that that we
forgot entirely about how we do security
like uh the S and MCP it stands for
security.
like authorization, integrity checks, uh
authentication, identification, those
stuff that like normally people always
get. Now we completely forgot about
them. And like we've seen some apps like
not on Google but basically a chatbot
assistant that were helping you with
your uh data inside your account and you
basically say hey what what's my uh la
last history search or something like
that and it was giving you the data and
then you just say but what's the user ID
da da da history search and because the
API that they hook was uh having like a
a tool uh like search uh user history
and then user ID and they were trusting
the LLM like a probabilistic machine to
actually get the right tool calls and
they were not trying to think about that
this could be influenced by the user and
so the goal here in term of security is
just to say the user asked me that so
the tool code call needs to be
influenced by which user it is and have
the AI never trying to guess the user ID
or implement that into the the tool as
an argument. However, so many people uh
do that. They trust the LM. Well, we we
we saw that a little bit, you know, in
some of the AIS we've hacked. If you get
into the the deeper level of it, you'll
actually see from a technical
implementation perspective, um the the
companies stripping out data from the
because a lot of times they, you know,
do an API call, they dump the data back
into the LLM and parse it out, but
they'll actually be like, okay, we need
to remove some of this metadata that's
in the APIs and stuff like that. Um and
that's why it's important to to do you
know the research that you did very
thoroughly uh in this event and in other
um events Ronnie of really understanding
every bit of what the model sees you
know and and down to okay you know the
model got this you know object back you
know from from the codeact flow or
whatever you know what exactly does this
have what are all the properties you
know what can I what can I get it to
yoink out of there um to use while
excation yeah one one key way to do that
is often to ask what the ID is for
things I've noticed that like even Grock
will like sometimes accidentally leak
like some of that metadata from like
some tweets that come back. It'll be
like I've had it because often it'll
reference a bunch of tweets. I've had it
say like and in tweet 1 2 5 6 7 8 9 10
uh you know like uh it said this and and
I'm like 65. Yeah. It does this. Yeah.
Yeah. So it it has the ID for the user
and the tweet which is fine. Those are
public because like you can see those in
the API but it's really funny. And so
that's actually a strategy I use when
I'm chatting with it and it's coming
back with like documents or other data.
I'll be like, "Yeah, what was the ID for
that?" And sometimes it'll have it and
that's kind of interesting. That's
that's very interesting and could
definitely be a useful gadget for um
Idor, you know, uh identification, uh
getting the IDs needed for that. Let's
move to Yeah, let's move to exfiltration
and sensitive action. Yeah. So, just to
wrap this back together, we went down a
bunch of rabbit holes. Um, we're talking
like we talked with Zach and we're kind
of recapping here that um, you know, in
our opinion the kind of the components
of an AI exploit are often the delivery,
what access does it have to data or
other things and then the either
exfiltration or sensitive actions. And
um, I think you know for us and the for
Google specifically they cared the most
about that last piece and I think that's
often what we were looking for is how
can we extrate this data which it you
know there's a million different ways
any any way it can communicate out any
way it can send sensitive data. So
sometimes those are native to the app
via tools like send email, send text
message, make a phone call. Um and then
there are of course the other ways which
are like create a link requires user
interaction. um create a markdown link,
which doesn't often these type of
things. But anyways, um when it comes to
those sensitive actions that can be
taken, it goes from a few small things
like modifying user object or modifying
uh objects into this app in the agent
space, it becomes modify anything you
want for anyone's account because if
they're logged in with their cookies as
their agent is acting on their behalf,
all of a sudden it can take actions in
any of the systems they have access to.
And so that's going to be a huge problem
going forward. Oh, also super something
super interesting um about like how
agents work is basically you have like
all the tool codes, you have the prompt
and everything, but you have the model
and like a lot of people and companies
used to swap the model, but then the the
model are like so are so different from
one another that the chain of thoughts
will be way more different and also they
are not specifically trained to the same
kind of prompts and therefore like just
swapping the model will have worse
results or better results, right? We
noticed that in this event between Flash
and Pro, right? Yeah. But you can
actually use that as a security bypass
of a lot of different uh stuff like I
cannot say but that that that they
implement uh and just from one model to
another they will not be trained to
understand those security concept
because the development teams are going
faster than what uh we can do in
security and because we barely
understand as an industry how those
models will work with certain prompts.
um that by the end of the day, you can
have like so much bypass just by
changing the version of the model.
Absolutely. Yeah, definitely good
takeaways there. Um we're going to take
five now. When we come back, we're going
to go ahead and talk about just sort of
rapid fire what kind of takeaways we got
from talking to other hackers at this
event. You know, whether it be
vulnerabilities that they found at the
event or the, you know, the time that we
spent talking to the hackers about bones
that they found outside of the event and
also why the event is so different that
others. Yeah, dude. We have a lot of
stuff to cover with that and also the
Google VRP. So, let's grab some water
and we'll get back in five. Sure.
All right, gents. We're back. Uh, so
essentially what I was hoping for this
segment was, you know, at these live
hacking events all the time, we are
talking to other hackers about the
vulnerabilities they found. We're kind
of gaining intel. Obviously, we're we're
finding bugs at this live hacking event.
So, um I've got a list of like takeaways
and and to be fair, you know, a lot of
people always say like, "Oh, these these
top names in Bug Bounty, they they get
so much more um you know, bounties and
and stuff like that because they're
wellknown." And to be honest, one of the
one of the reasons, and that it's up for
debate, but definitely one of the things
that's 100% true, if you have the
privilege to go to a live hacking event,
your skill level just goes like this
because you get to like talk to so many
people about what exploits they're
finding, um, you know, what
vulnerabilities and um, and that's just
a really big learning experience. So,
I've got I always, you know, at the end
of these events, I always try to take
all my takeaways, consolidate them into
a little doc, and then pepper them on
the podcast over the, you know, over the
next couple of episodes. What's
interesting in this event like the
Google events is that um all the
researchers are not I would say well
known on the Twitter community or like
not a lot of people follow them but they
are like amazing super technical and I
wish like more people knew them. They
don't have a podcast. Like none of them.
None of them. Not incredible thinkers. I
I took so much heat. So So let me just
let me just now shut the freak up,
Ronnie. Um so when we went to the Google
live hacking event, they were like,
"Okay, we're going to do research
introductions. Everybody say your name
and you know what you're up to in life."
And I'm went first first of course cuz
you know uh and and so I was like, "Hey,
I'm Justin, you know, full-time book
bounty hunter. Also, I have a podcast.
Uh you should check it out." Super
casual. super casual, just super chill.
And uh and then, you know, I think it's
Ronnie that goes next. Ronnie goes next.
Hey, I'm Ronnie Carter. You know, I run
this startup or whatever. I don't have a
podcast. And everyone was like, "Oh, so
funny." And then literally every single
person for the rest of the event said,
"I don't have a podcast except for
except for Reso, who does have a
podcast." There was one or two people in
there who who put it on their head,
which I thought was very uh cool of
them. Was it Sivan? Yeah. And he was
like, "And I listened to Justin's
podcast." Yeah. That was that made me
feel better. But then I took heat for
the rest of the event. Everyone was
like, "All right, if you have a podcast,
you go over this way and if you don't
have a like the program manager of
Google roasted you show and tell so many
times so many times. That was amazing.
That that became a meme." Yeah. Um, best
meme over here.
It's just you.
Justin is the meme. Oh jeez. Yeah. Well,
let's also talk about that really quick.
Awards. Obviously, the full group here.
Um, the four of us won MVH together. Um,
Kieran got uh most creative report which
was stunning and one of the most
brilliant out of the box thinkings I've
ever seen. We're going to definitely
blog about that, right? 100%. Um, and
then Ronnie won uh best memer award. So,
we actually took three out of four
awards at this event. Yeah, the second
place we didn't get, dude. Yeah, Val
Valentino Valentino took it and I I'm
really interested to talk to him. I was
hoping I could snag him and bring him on
the pod. Um, but he he had some plans
and such. So we'll uh we'll try to catch
up with him a different time. Um but as
far as you know technical takeaways from
the event, there were just a couple
things and I you know as we were working
with other hackers throughout this event
um you know sharing stories you know
related to the the the attack surface
that we're working on from other
programs and and the findings that we
found at this event. Um one of the
things that came up that was super
interesting to me was that and maybe you
Mac users might know this more than
others. I did not know that you could
not have a file with uh the same you
know word uh uppercase and lowercase in
a folder in Mac like the case
sensitivity does not matter on Mac
because if you try to name a file
something with a different case it will
not let you right so if you have a file
named ABC you cannot have lower case you
cannot have a file named capital ABC
that's right on Mac which is just super
weird and very inconsistent with Linux
and Windows Um, and there I was talking
to another researcher there and he had
utilized that in a in an environment to
cause a vulnerability. So I I just when
I saw that I was like wow this is like
so niche and we often see casing issues
in security um causing overlaps and and
stuff like that and overrides um and you
know it's a little bit less relevant to
like server architecture because nothing
runs off of Mac you know from a server
perspective but when you're attacking
local machines then there's definitely
some impact there. Yeah. Yeah. One
takeaway for me. Sure. Yeah. So, one
thing I was going to mention was I think
that I noticed that there kind of on
some from those same researches that
you're talking about that the things
they were looking at the interesting
vulnerabilities were in this kind of um
tool that allows you to go from zero to
app. And I think that there are a lot of
those already, right? Like there's
vzero, there's replet, there's lovable,
um there's bolt. These apps basically
allow you to use an LLM to go from zero
to deployment. And what and I think
what's interesting is that there is user
interaction or sorry there is user input
there and and also cases where there
could be prompt injection and it can
lead to things downstream at the
deployment step because if you think
about deployment it's basically codeex
exec in many levels. Yeah. And so one
it's highly impactful. two, um, another
kind of key thing that's unique across
things in this event and, uh, mentioned
by other researchers and in the apps I
just mentioned is the ability to share.
And so like sometimes um, user trust,
there's a user trust barrier there that
it's like, of course, if someone is
sending you code to execute, it might
not be safe, right? But in other in
other places there's not. And that was
actually one thing um, that some of that
one of your bugs relied on that I think
is really interesting to know. Like I
know that we talk a lot about hey in
these live hacking events you get u like
more intimate with these uh programs and
you learn what they care about deeply.
Yeah. Uh but also a lot of these um
basically deployment or CI/CD related AI
features and apps are going to have tool
calls. I don't think you were in this
conversation. I was talking to Yakob and
and he um has been uh kind of interested
in and finding SSRF in AI related
deployment things where where there are
tool calls. Interesting. Yeah. And so I
don't um I don't know even know the
technical details there but if you think
about uh CI/CD in general it does have
to often fetch files either locally
fetch files remote zip and unzip things
remote or locally right I think those
are like very interesting high impact um
features that could you imagine like
asking the LLM and then just seeing it
like print out AWS metadata on the way
oh my gosh that I'm sure someone has
found that I'm sure just because of the
web fetch feature right and if it's
running inside of a cloud environment
that that'll be awesome Mon, Ronnie,
what what have you guys got? I go for
it. Go I think a lot of my technical
takeaways were actually just from
hanging out with this guy because we
have such different uh ways we hack.
Yeah. Uh I'm I think a lot less
technical than him. I tend to go for
more like weird bugs, you know, as you
can tell. Just weird stuff. Weird stuff.
And you actually sleep. Yeah.
I don't I don't have midnight red bows,
you know. Yeah. But uh I I think it
really the big takeaway for me is you
need both like not just the the sheer
technical skill. You need creativity and
not just creativity but you need like a
due diligence in maybe how how
thoroughly you look at uh these various
kinds of uh systems like because I
before this event I had this idea in my
head of of like it was all going to be
kind of uh probabilistic prompts. Yeah.
that might work maybe 50% of the time.
And then he comes over here with this
like he's read papers, he's done all
this like tokenization stuff that I had
no idea could like reduce the
probability aspect to like near
certainty. M um and it made me realize
of course AI models are just they're
they're probabilistic but they behave in
very predictable ways and they are
systems that we can work with like you
work with a web server like an AI model
is just another bit of code. Yeah. And
that like blew my mind. I think the
creativity piece is really interesting
because your bug they paid really well
was extremely creative in my opinion. It
was like hard tech LLM tech you know
like interesting kind of social
engineering aspects and all that and I
think that that was true for so many of
the show and tells that I just would
have never imagined some of those
vulnerabilities. Do you think that
there's like kind of room for even more
creativity? It kind of hearkens back to
some of the CSS injection stuff based
from a long time ago. Well, for for sure
and I think one of the interesting
pieces about Google is they take their
their security extremely seriously and
they value or I think they have a better
understanding than most programs do on
how much user action you can get, you
know, like you can get a lot of user
interaction, you know, and and at their
scale. Yeah. At their scale. and and you
um you know and they really value having
uh exploits built that are beautiful and
clean and very convincing. Right? So so
I I I'll be I'll be general about this.
This is something I've used in my Google
hacking uh you know over the past three
months as I've been focusing on them as
my main target. Um is that they really
value when you go the extra mile and
find for example like UI elements that
you can manipulate to make your attack a
little bit more convincing. Yeah. Right?
And maybe you just pull in this little
I've got this little thing that can hide
this thing or like I can, you know, push
this off the screen so the user has to
go do whatever, you know, all all of
those pieces where you're making your
attack just a little bit more convincing
and clean. Um, really I think goes the
extra mile with Google to to to prove
impact. Yeah. And I mean I I'm sure that
in a perfectly logical world it wouldn't
affect the bounty, but it's like of
course it affects the likelihood of
exploitation and so it does impact the
bounty at the end of the day it does.
And so I think Yeah. I I think as far as
other technical takeaways go for me, you
know, you you talked about AI and how AI
has to get integrated into these
different product groups. And I think
one of the things that we saw uh at this
event, which I did get clearance to say
by the way, I I'm not going to go into
full details, but I did talk about that
and they said I could say this was that
there's a lot of eye framework that
happens, right? Because you are, you
know, you've got established products
and then you're pasting, you know, AI
into it, right? And um so for those of
you hackers that are more familiar with
uh client side stuff uh there are a lot
of attack vectors that you can put into
place when you have an iframe you know
on a page and and have getting a
reference to that frame you know what
what uh sandboxing properties that frame
has you know what kind of permissions
that iframe has um we saw that used in
the event and when I was speaking with
other hackers you know outside of the
event as well it's something that is
pretty consistent across the whole LLM
space um and that was that was a And I
consider myself very very very well
acquainted with iframes in client side
you know permission stuff. There were
like three things that I learned that I
can't give the specific details on right
now but I will bring to you in the
future um about how iframes work in
these key environments. And it just
shows that even somebody who is a client
side hacker you know thoroughly um
there's so much more you can learn about
all that. And I think I touched on this
um a few a few weeks ago with Joseph,
but there is there's a lot of like chat
widgets in NLM now and they use Post
message. Yeah. Always use Post message.
So client side is like goes hand inhand
with AI like perfectly. Really does. It
really does. and and uh yeah and then
you know trying to attack these AI
components from the server side just
generally speaking it comes down to uh a
similar scenario which is are they going
to integrate are they going to integrate
AI directly into their core APIs maybe
probably not you know they're probably
going to stand up a different API server
and have their all of their LLM stuff
siloed in there and then kind of
integrate it on the product level with
with uh with their you know production
APIs for their primary product at least
that's the architecture I've seen across
many companies nowadays. Um so you know
the extra mile then comes you know when
you understand where those APIs live
what kind of functionality and how
they're integrating with the main
product. Is it just on the client side
you know via grabbing information piping
it into the prompts you know pushing it
out to the LLM getting the response or
is there some direct integration with
the LLM um and that's where things get a
little bit more interesting. Yeah. Yeah.
Um, all right. So, the one other note
that I'll just kind of toss out there
for the uh for the viewership is that I
think I really this AI um explosion
that's been happening as it grows is
really reminiscent to me of what
happened with web 3 as well, which is,
you know, and I'm sure all the
old-timers are like, "No duh. This is
how any progress happens." But, you
know, when web 3 came on the scene,
we're like, "Oh, wow." You know, very
cool technology, lots of fun stuff. I
took the deep dive you know on Ethereum
hacking and and uh found some you know
contract level vulnerabilities. Um but
then you know as I started looking at it
more and more we need to integrate web 3
and AI into our existing web 2
infrastructure and a lot of people
follow the shiny object of AI or web 3
when really traditional web 2
vulnerabilities surrounding these
products is uh neglected andor you know
overlooked by shiny object syndrome. Um
and I think that is probably a higher
level principle that we can apply to any
progressions that happen in technology
when u you know the a new core piece of
technology is brought in mass to the to
the people is that um how that
technology gets integrated into existing
infrastructure is absolutely pivotal.
Yeah. Before we because I know we're
getting close to the end here. We keep
talking about how we're going to talk
about the abuse abuse ERP. There there
were some positives and some negatives
from the event. Yeah. One one more and
then we'll go to that. Okay. Um because
there's a there's a nice pivot into this
which is uh let's talk a little bit more
about the live hacking event with Google
and we all worked together as a team at
this event. Yeah. What and we won. Give
me some guys. Let's go. Let's let's go
ahead and do this one more time. Let's
go. Let's go. There we go. Um what why
did we win? you know,
um, you know, why why why did we win?
What what what were the pivotal pieces
of success for our team, you think, in
this live hacking event? Um, you know,
one of the ones that came to my mind is
we did a decent amount of delegation,
right? What you know, we would split out
different pieces of scope. Well, I will
say Justin did a good amount of
delegation.
And this actually makes me think I think
for people that are going to team up,
even if it's only two people, if there
is a more conscientious or more detail-
oriented person, yeah, let them direct.
One, let them bring you back when you go
down a rabbit hole. I think that you did
that really well for us. Two, let them
delegate uh and kind of prioritize. And
maybe maybe that's not necessarily
conscientiousness. Maybe that's just
more experience. But I think that you
did a fantastic job of doing that. And
it made me realize how much of a
strength that is in your tool set. Like
obviously everyone knows that Justin is
you know probably one of the best well
probably the best bug hunter across all
platforms. I mean, but I mean, it's
true. And I think that and I um I didn't
know that was a strength of yours. Like
I knew that you had extreme technical
chops and I knew that you had extreme
dedication. Like you're able to lock in
I think more than most other hackers,
but but in fact I didn't realize that
actually I mean pri prioritization is
key. Of course we're all pretty high
agency. We're all pretty good at
prioritizing. But I think that you're on
like another level of prioritization and
being able to like basically you shared
that superpower with our team is what
I'm trying to say. Yeah.
There was like several times where
Joseph and I got the shiny object
syndrome. We're looking at something
stupid. Like it was completely not the
right thing, but but I mean there were
still like potential blogs. Like I think
it was not the best use of our time at
the time. And then Justin comes along.
He's like, "Guys, this go back to go
back to the thing." And I was like, "I
appreciate." Listen guys, there was and
I think I can say this. I think this I
think they're fine with this. If not,
we'll bleep it. But there was an 100%
bonus on in scope. you know, like
essentially anything that was in scope
was the bounty was doubled, you know, so
like we don't want to let that
opportunity like slip in while you're
reading, you know, like I I appreciate
that, guys. And I also appreciate you,
you know, collaborating with me on that.
Like you know what what we did several
times throughout the event was we came
together and and we did in the beginning
um you know hack separately or as offite
we did not. But then when we come on
site we work together and that makes it
less awkward when we're sharing stuff
too here. It's like you're not scared to
say something. You're not scared.
Exactly. It does. And then, you know,
when we would meet, we would come
together, and then we would say, "Okay,
I've got six leads, you know, from from
this side. You've got some, you've got
some, you've got some." And then we
prioritize them. And then we would break
them out. And we would say, "Okay, you
know, client side stuff, you know, we're
going to have Mon look at that. You
know, we've got some some some really
deep, you know, LLM agency stuff. We're
going to have, you know, Ronnie and
Reszo look at. Um, I'm calling you
Ronnie. These two by their hacker
handles, Lupin. Um, and you know, and
then we kind of we kind of break out
those different roles. Um, and I think
that was I think that resulted in a lot
of good output for us. You know, we were
able to prioritize what needed to be
hacked on and who was the most well
equipped even if that was Rooney's lead,
right? And then we give it to Mon
because he's got this sharing of
information was huge because there's
several times where I was like okay I
had this uh like going back to the
delivery the data access the exploration
where I had like two pieces and then
Ronnie happened to have the middle bit
that I needed to finish the chain and
that was like so good for this event.
Yeah. And uh I I think like something
really interesting about this team is
that we have like so many different ways
to look at a scope and uh also about our
hacking mindset are really not similar.
So we really complete one another and
also from a skill set perspective too
and we are not going to have like the
same
theories. For instance, I know that
Justin when we hike together is like way
more methodological than me. Uh but I go
to the really naive questions and
fundamentals of like what what is the
app doing and like hey can we try that
and sometime is like no you can't do
that because that that that and
afterwards it's like unless this
happened wait exactly there's a bug
that's very I mean that happened often
and and I think I don't fight with
anyone quite as much as I fight with you
when we're hacking I'm like Ronnie this
is dumb let's not do this and you And
then I'm like, "Okay, okay, okay, okay.
Solid, solid." You know, it's like two
knives sharpening on one another. It's
like confrontation to better build. Like
it's like And to be fair to myself,
inversely so as well. Right. Of course.
Okay. Of course. Like that. That's the
most important thing. You don't need to
hack with people that are exactly in
your same skill set or have like your
same hacking mindset. You need like
people really far apart from you so you
can complete one another. And that's
like each team has like their uh master
post exploit guy, the automation guy,
the the the creative weight guy that
comes at the end and like, "Hey guys, I
was working for so many hours on that
thing. Help me." You wake you wake up
and Ronnie's all like, "How do you
know?" One of the nights we we went to
bed and we woke up and Ronnie was going
to bed. They were like, "Shit."
No, actually I think one thing that
really we haven't mentioned, it's like
not a technical thing, but I think that
there's a lot of a deep respect for each
other here and I think that that I think
that actually played a role in this
event. There were several times, Justin,
that I feel like um you would not have
came out of your hole or pivoted to look
at something. Yeah. But you were you
respect me enough. I was like, "No, you
need to read this message that Jim put
in this chat and you need to read it
aggressively and it's very you like oh
that is interesting. I'm going to go sit
with them." You know, they were like
that happened. That was really good. Um,
and I definitely I definitely agree with
that. Um, so pivoting away from our team
strategy and more into the Google live
hacking event experience. There's lots
of things we can talk about. You know,
we talked a little bit about him with
Zach. I I don't I don't know if you guys
were listening in. I know you were in
the room, but um, we we talked a good
bit about, you know, the onetoone
engineer ratio, engineer to hacker ratio
at this event, which I think was
massive. And Ronnie, I know that you
essentially claimed Gabbor. Yeah. You
know, the whole event like Ronnie just
found a Google engineer and was like
just grabbed him and just like let me
put you up team now. Yeah. Like and
dude, it's funny cuz he came over for
drinks last night too after the event.
And I was like, "Aren't you sick of
Ronnie?"
And that was by Ronnie. Exactly. I keep
coming back for more. Yeah. No, he he
he's amazing and he really helped me out
uh during the the entire event. Um and
that's where you really feel like a part
of the security team like you are an
extension of security team like most u
event the security team acts like a bit
adversarial to you in in like oh we know
better than you but we're not going to
give you the the answer and it's just
making our work longer and we are like
on so much timesensitive engagement that
we need to to to actually get our works
done right but Google really understands
that because most of the security team
has been either bug hunters or CTF
players. That's crazy that that's true.
And you're right, it is. Yeah. And they
know like what would make our job easier
and so they just give us to us where
where where are you at? Oh, you're here.
Okay. Uh you know, try this, try this,
you know, and and that that's something
that they do outside of the live hacking
events, too, where when you submit a bug
to Google, the reason why these people
are really proficient and we get
impressed when we come on site and work
with them is because that's what they're
doing every day with our bug reports.
you know, they take our bug reports,
they go in the code, they escalate them.
I I have made I'll be clear with this
number. I have made over $5,000 more in
just the past couple months because a
Google engineer came in and said, "Oh,
actually, you can also use this this way
and escalate it like this." And then I
got a bigger bounty, you know, and
that's like that's pretty sick. Like you
never see that anywhere. Yeah. They they
they do not try to be against you or
make your your job harder. They want to
give you all the tools because they want
to see like this creative vulnerability
and they love the technical and they're
like passionate people and so they going
to help you and they they will you know
I think it's that's what they said the
googly vibe of trying to cheer people up
instead of trying to take people down.
Yeah. Uh and and that's amazing uh in in
those events. So I I want to do either
of you guys have comments on that or
should we swing to abuse? No swing to
abuse. Yeah. Okay. So one of the one of
the things that is a little bit tricky
for anybody who has worked with Google
before is uh there are specifically on
AI stuff too. specifically on AI stuff
as well. Absolutely. Is that there are,
you know, there's lots of different uh
programs that Google runs in their
vulnerability um research VRP. What is
it? Vulnerability. Yeah, research. I was
like for a second I'm blanking on it.
Vulnerability research program. Um and
two of them, the two ones that most
align with, you know, traditional bug
bounty, you know, excluding like kernel
level work on like, you know, Android
and stuff like that are the Google VRP
and the abuse VRP. Um, and the payouts
for those two uh VRPs are vastly
different. Um, and what'll happen
sometimes is you'll submit a report,
you'll be like, "Okay, I believe that
this is uh going to be accepted by
Google VRP and get this, you know, crazy
bounty." And then that gets accepted by
Abuse VRP and the bounty is much lower.
Um, and we spent a lot of time talking
with the team about that whole concept
at this event. And I think it makes a
lot more sense to me now than it did
before. And I know that the team is
going to be putting out some more clear
guidelines on what constitutes abuse and
what constitutes um Google VRP and uh in
the future and I'm really looking
forward to that. But one of the things
that I I wanted to tell the the people
about that is one you know read the docs
very thoroughly but two abuse is not a a
punishment for the hacker. the abuse of
VRP is actually extremely nuanced and
will pay for a lot more things than
normal bug bounty will. Um so you know
that that whole I was talking to the
manager of abuse actually and they
report up through the trust and safety
team which is the same team that deals
with like you know if somebody's like
cyber bullying you you know like and
they are very much interested in like
how can our products be abused to affect
the user negatively whether that be a
technical exploit or whether that be you
know something else. Um, and so what
Google will do is we'll pay out for a
lot of things that are out of scope of
normal bug bounty programs through the
uh abuse channel. Um, so it's a
double-edged sword, but it does cut in
our favor sometimes. Yeah, I was going
to say, so basically what we're trying
to say is there's some pros and some
cons. Yeah, I would say the biggest cons
are that the middle ground is sometimes
unclear. Yeah. Like for example, a
vulnerability that a lot of bug bounty
programs would accept and would and what
I would not consider abuse is like
leaked API keys. Yeah. some of those in
Google are considered abuse. Um like
when they're when there's not like a
direct heavily security impact, but if
there's a you know heavily monetization
impact, you know, Google's like, "Oh,
that's abuse." And and it's just like a
flat $500 bounty, right? And sometimes I
think there actually is more impact
there than what is paid out. And I think
it's similar with AI where the middle
ground between abuse versus Chrome VRP
or Google VRP. Yeah. Um I think that can
lead to frustration. Uh but but again
I'm like oh I'm I'm overall extremely
happy with the program and and one of
the things that they that came to my
attention you know during this event was
obviously there's a lot of things that
we wouldn't even get paid for at all
that we do get paid for through abuse
which is which is great. Um but there's
there's definitely uh a nuance to uh the
way that they define uh where
vulnerabilities originate from. Right.
And one of the big things that they they
said to us about that was if if a
feature is working as intended but can
be abused for a negative purpose that is
abuse right if a feature is not working
as intended right uh then that falls
under Google VRP. So it it is your
responsibility as the researcher in in
some degree right and not necessarily
your responsibility the Google team will
do the research as well but the best
most winsome practice for you as the
researcher is to you know try to clearly
show hey there is a security
misconfiguration here you know this
product is not working as intended uh
there somebody made a mistake and that's
why there's a vulnerability not I can
utilize some of these business logic
errors you know that that are are
present in Google's products to
accomplish on malicious purpose and
maybe the impact is the same across both
of them but Google handles those very
differently uh and that can be
disappointing for the researcher
sometimes but uh also very valuable if
you know how to weaponize it properly
and also if there is a technical fix
that doesn't change the way the product
works and uh and like it still works as
intended then it might have more chances
to go to VIP than abuse uh because um it
proves that this is a technical problem
and not an abuse of the the feature.
I think the fact that um they pay for
well-written reports which have to
include remediation is your chance as a
hacker to say here's where I think it
there is a technical fix and then that's
going to basically also let it be led
more likely to be in Google VRP instead
of abuse. Yeah. I I I wish I had sat
down with you guys and discussed this.
Maybe maybe I did. I the whole event was
such a whirlwind, but I sat down with a
couple other hackers at the event and
was like, we're like looking at their
reports to Google and I was like, "Oh my
gosh, they don't have the remediation
steps in the root cause analysis
section, they are losing, you know, a
1.5x multiplier on their bounty
because," and I' I've shouted this out
on the pod before. It is one of the most
unbelievable things that I've ever seen
in bug bounty that Google offers
extremely competitive bounties and then
will 1.5 exit if you write root cause
analysis and uh remediation steps. Yep.
You know, and I'm just like this is such
a big hack that anybody who's hacking
Google, you know, needs to know. You
must go to the Google
VRP description page and read exactly
what will land you that 1.5x multiplier
and then just put those sections in the
report and you just 1.5x your bounties.
Like how crazy is that? That's freaking
sick, right? And AI is like very nice at
a little like first pass at that. You
should clean it up. You should make it
really good. You should make it high
quality because they're paying you so
well for it. Yeah. It's worth of your
It's worth your time. It It help It
helps me too because I spend a lot of
time building a really quality PC a lot
of time. like maybe sometimes my reports
are [__] but um I build a quality PC
and I want that PC to speak for itself,
right? And that's sort of where I take
pride as a hacker, but this fact that
they and the a high quality PC is
accepted or is expected by their their
middle tier, right? There's like if you
submit a particularly [__] report,
they're going to de downgrade it, you
know, they're going to reduce the
payment by 50%. If you submit an okay
report, you know, it's normal. And then
if you said an exceptional report, it's
it's it's 1.5x that middle ground, you
know, it requires that a PC be good. You
know, that that's there. And I was like,
that's that's reasonable. So, you know,
I put my normal amount of effort into
the PC. But then when I'm writing the
report, I was like, wow, you know, they
are really incentivizing me to write a
good report here financially, and that
makes it so much easier for me to like
get over that that hacker report block
and and lock into writing. and and and I
just think that's something that
probably gives them a large return on
investment from a hacker perspective
because their reports that they're
getting are like going to be much higher
quality. But also like something really
strange when you hack on Google is that
their threat modeling is really weird
from like externally and you really need
to sat down with them and ask the
questions even before you even try
finding a vulnerability that they are
pretty accessible. you you can ping them
and just ask like okay is for that
specific product because the thread
model will change from one product to
another even if they look similar they
don't have the same market purpose and
so the thread modeling is different and
so for each product sometimes you need
to go in depth and like ask them or
figure out like what's the thread
modeling like what's the real thing that
will impact uh this asset and once you
figure out it's way easier to to hack on
them and I think like most of the people
I talked to that were frustrated with
Google bugy program and I was also at
the beginning is that we couldn't
understand like what was the threat
modeling because from one website to
another it will change entirely but once
you get that and you know how to ask the
the questions uh then uh you get a
better return investment of your time I
think as a general rule of thumb they
really like data leaks in terms of like
things that affect users information and
PII
is like huge. They really prioritize
them. Yeah, they do. They do. And and if
you can prove that very cleanly, then
it's very highly rewarded, you know, and
and one other thing that I wanted to
mention before we move on from abuse is
is that a lot of the AI stuff ends up in
abuse, right? Because it's it's uh a
little bit less hard tech, a little bit
less, you know, concrete. Um and I think
when one of the one of the good
challenges for us uh when we're
attacking Google AI is how do we get
this you know h how do we try to craft
an exploit such that uh this is a clear
security boundary issue you know and and
then you know land ourselves in the in
the Google VRP program. Um so yeah good
good thoughts there. Um do you guys have
anything else that you wanted to talk
about about the Google VRP uh program? I
mean we got some sick swag.
the the the the Google offices are sick.
Maybe I'll we'll put some pictures up on
the screen right now um of the offices
that were amazing. Um and the you know,
I just felt very privileged to be there.
Obviously, we're in we're in Tokyo,
which is like my [__] What and and they
let us go in there and record. So, huge
props to that. Yeah, that was awesome.
I'd love to record at the um the Google
headquarters. You guys have any other
comments about that experience, the live
hacking experience? Um I think it's like
really different that out of other live
events because we are like a really
small community at Google and um and
like the faces that we see are so
rereshing depending on like according
like when compared to other live hacking
events and what I really like is that
everyone has basically the kind of the
same mindset and humility uh when we
talk to one another and like a lot of
respect and passion And uh it makes like
the event even more cozy but when you
see like uh the total rewards that was
given it doesn't really change that much
I would say like the impact that the
researcher had like even if it's small
community and that's something
interesting that Google uh managed to do
is that they managed to cherrypick
researchers that goes well together in a
room and that managed to find like
really impactful creative stuff. Yeah. I
wanna I wanna I want to run the
calculation really quick because they
said it was like 230,000 or something
like that
across it's like the average bounty is
like that's an unbelievable statistic
though and I know that our average
bounty across this group was higher than
that uh by a good bit. Um and and so
that was uh I mean the bounties are
there the the competition is small. I
think one of the things that blew my
mind as well is that they said that
there's almost zero duplicates like
Because in the nar the scope for this
event was really small. Yeah, it was
pretty narrow. I think was Zach earlier.
You said 25. I think there was like 15.
15 what? Uh researchers. Oh yeah. Was it
really? Yeah, I think there was between
15 and 20. I think you mentioned 25.
Yeah, earlier. Really? Wow, dude. I mean
in the chat there's only 22 people and
there's Google in there. Oh wow, that's
crazy, man. Yeah, it is a very small
group. Um, but yeah, I mean the the
bounties were were very quality and
uh the duplicate levels almost nothing
which is uh really impressive as well
despite the scope being you know as far
as Google's vastness the scope is pretty
small and still very little duplicates.
Yeah. And that just goes to show as well
that Google has so many products. Yeah.
And to find this many bugs on that small
snip of the scope kind of indicates that
you look at everything else there's so
much waiting there. Yeah, that's true. I
I definitely think that's true for their
VRP. You didn't mention that. Or sorry,
for their GCP for the cloud VRP, they
they they released that last year um and
upped all the bounties on it. I think
the stuff was probably in scope before,
but it was just like a normal or like a
low tier asset. Now it's a very high
tier asset. So if people um are used to
looking at things like um like AWS, for
example, I think that the amount of
competition on GCP is way less than AWS
and the new bounties are significant. So
yeah, absolutely. Well, guys, really
really awesome event. I had a blast.
Thanks for teaming up with uh with this
is like your like your favorite country
to visit, dude. I'm not gonna lie, man.
the last event in Tokyo. Um, you know,
Hacker One did an event in Tokyo and uh
I believe that Target is public for
that, but maybe I'll just hold off
saying it. It is. Yeah, it's public.
PayPal, you know, I I ranked third in
like the and then second in like the two
prior PayPal events and the scope that
they had for the Tokyo event was just
did not match with me very much. And I
was so disappointed because it's like
that's my [__] you know, like and and
so I'm really really I'm really glad to
be in Tokyo this time, you know, walking
away with the uh NBA trophy, even though
this one goes to Ronnie, right? Yeah,
Ronnie let me have the last one from
Vegas. So, uh but we'll see. Hopefully,
we can convince him to send us another
one. Um do you guys got any any final
closing comments or should we go run
around Tokyo now?
Let's go. And uh I'm glad to be on the
podcast.
All right, that's a wrap. That's the
pun.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, uh, or
if you want to support the show, head
over to
ctbb.show/isord. You can hop in the
community. There's lots of great
highlevel hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes,
hackalongs, exclusive content, and a
full-time hunters guild if you're a
full-time hunter. It's a great time.
Trust me. All right, I'll see you there.